<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Manon Kempermann</title>
    <link>https://www.manonkempermann.eu/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Manon Kempermann</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 10:23:21 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.manonkempermann.eu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Alignment or why we need to think about AI safety</title>
      <link>https://www.manonkempermann.eu/blog/25_01_intro_alignment_problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 10:23:21 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.manonkempermann.eu/blog/25_01_intro_alignment_problem/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I want to begin this blog with an outline of the problem with AI and why we need to pay attention to AI safety.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, I caught up with a friend who countered my interest in AI safety by claiming that this focus was “so German”—always overly cautious, regulating everything too much, and thereby slowing down innovation and blocking AI’s potential. While his argument has some merit, I believe there’s a deeper dimension to how AI could go wrong—one that goes beyond misuse, which was essentially his concern. This dimension is referred to as the alignment problem, and it’s what we’ll explore today.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I write this blog</title>
      <link>https://www.manonkempermann.eu/blog/24_52_kick_of_blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 10:22:41 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.manonkempermann.eu/blog/24_52_kick_of_blog/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I started studying Data Science and AI, I was almost entirely interested in the application of AI in other domains of science such as biology or environmental science. I had never really programmed before and did not see myself as a computer scientist. However, having some knowledge about AI seemed promising in these times and liking STEM subjects more than social science, I decided to give it a try.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CV</title>
      <link>https://www.manonkempermann.eu/page/cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.manonkempermann.eu/page/cv/</guid>
      
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;manon-kempermann&#34;&gt;Manon Kempermann&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;education&#34;&gt;Education&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BSc &lt;strong&gt;Data Science and AI&lt;/strong&gt;, Saarland University, Germany (2023-2026)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Member of Honours Program of the faculty (top 5% students)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Average grade: 1.1 (~3.9 GPA)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Relevant Class work:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MIPS assembly&lt;/strong&gt;: Rock, Paper, Scissors including random number simulator&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;C&lt;/strong&gt;: Image edge detector, PageRank&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Java&lt;/strong&gt;: 2048 Game, Route planner, Compiler for C subset to MIPS assembly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scottish Qualification Certificate, Kilgraston School, Scotland, UK (2021-2022)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dresden Trust Scholar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Highers in Mathematics (A), Chemistry (A), Human Biology (A), Business Management (A), Latin (A), German (A)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;experience&#34;&gt;Experience&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Research Assistant at the Interdisciplinary Institute for Societal Computing (I2SC) in Saarbrücken, Germany, working on LLM-Alignment in electoral advice (05/2024 - ongoing)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tutor Core Lecture &amp;ldquo;Elements of Data Science and AI&amp;rdquo; at Saarland University (10/2024 - 03/2025)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spring School &amp;ldquo;Clinicum Digitale&amp;rdquo; for digital health at EKFZ Dresden, Germany (03/2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;volunteering&#34;&gt;Volunteering&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Accompanying seminars for weltwärts-volunteers as an alumna and teamer-in-training at the Internationaler Bund, Germany (01/2024 - ongoing)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
